<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Kitsune</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="race-kitsune.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/core/players-handbook/races/race-tiefling.xml" />
		</update>
		(source: https://www.dandwiki.com/wiki/Kitsune_(5e_Race))
	</info>

	<element name="Kitsune" type="Race" source="dandwiki" id="ID_RACE_KITSUNE">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">It has been a long time, children, but it is time to break
					back into the world. Know this: the world is ever changing. You may be
					the target of discrimination and hatred. Hopefully, those out in the world
					have learned from their egregious past and moved on. Do not hate someone
					for their skin. Do not hate someone for their past. Learn to live with
					them in the here and now because if you don't, happiness will never be
					attained in your life. —Tsukiko, a nine-tailed kitsune, to her people
					before sending out ambassadors to other race's kingdoms.</p>

			<h4>PHYSICAL DESCRIPTION</h4>
			<p>A kitsune has a stature similar to that of an elf, being a bit shorter,
					and lither than a typical human. In their natural form, they are much
					like anthropomorphic foxes. They usually have light colored fur, reddish
					brown, white, golden brown, though it isn't completely unheard of for
					them to possess black fur that covers their entire body. Their eyes range
					in color as well, though most have blue, green, or brown eyes. Albeit
					uncommon they may also have orange, purple, yellow, or even red eyes.
					They have mostly human-like hands with dark black claws at the ends of
					their fingers and paw pads on their feet and hands. A kitsune is born
					with a single tail, growing a new tail every 5-6 years starting when
					they reach adulthood at 16. However, a kitsune's age is very difficult
					to tell since they appear to stop aging in their early twenties and live
					to be a century and a half.</p>

			<h4>HISTORY</h4>
			<p>Kitsune are quite rare. They tend to hide their heritage while dealing
					with other races to avoid discrimination and hatred. There are many
					legends relating to powerful nine-tailed kitsune. Tending to be powerful
					sorcerers, it is said that kitsune are born tricksters and have
					nigh-infinite power by the time they are fully matured. Supposedly, the
					only way to kill a kitsune is to cut off all of its tails, but that is
					simply a tall tale. Due to the legend stating that a kitsune's tail
					contains power, they were nearly wiped out and most of them went into
					hiding. Only just getting back into the world after centuries of isolation,
					it is still the practice of some races to sever a kitsune's tail in hopes
					of obtaining power.</p>

			<h4>SOCIETY</h4>
			<p>Kitsune society used to be flourishing with mages and clerics. Since
					Kitsune are born with magic in their blood, it is common for them to
					seek to improve on what they are already gifted with. They used to be
					a very open people. Many of the legends of the Kitsune came from the
					Kitsune themselves, spinning tall tales of grand heroic mages and warriors.
					Other races didn't get along with Kitsune due to magic being relatively
					rare and all Kitsune being born with it. After the massive genocide
					against their race, they became largely secretive.</p>
			<p>After coming out of hiding, their faith in the world was restored after
					the Great Nine-Tailed Tsukiko led them away from their destruction.
					Most of the kitsune are still very secretive, albeit passionate about
					their causes. It is in their nature to be a bit of a trickster with
					people they get to know, and it isn't uncommon for their jokes to
					'go a little too far' in the eyes of other races. Other races are wary
					of these fox folk when they meet them. Many pose as humans in the world,
					having shape changing as an innate ability in their blood. Many kitsune
					go out to study magic or spread the word of their gods. Some simply want
					to spread the stories of their kind, valuing these great stories, kitsune
					bards to travel to other nations to tell their tales.</p>

			<h4>KITSUNE NAMES</h4>
			<p>Having had their society nearly exterminated, it is not all that uncommon
					for a kitsune to have names of other races. The names listed below are
					some traditional kitsune names.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Male Names:</strong> Akihiko, Daiki, Jirou, Kei, Osamu,
					Takeo, Yuudai</li>
				<li><strong>Female Names:</strong> Aya, Chinatsu, Eri, Mana, Ritsuko,
					Sachiko, Tsukiko</li>
			</ul>
			<h4>KITSUNE TRAITS</h4>
			<p>A race of anthropomorphic fox people who have magic in their blood and
					light shape-changing capabilities.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong>
				Your Charisma score increases by 2.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Kitsune reach adulthood
				at 16, cease physical aging in their early 20s and live to be a century
				and a half.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Due to their nature
				of being a bit mischievous, kitsune are often chaotic. Even the most
				skilled monks find it difficult to ignore the desire to be a bit
				mischievous at times, but they tend to approach the trick in a much more
				planned out and guided manner. Kitsune are known to be both good and evil.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Kitsune are generally on
				the smaller side of most humanoids ranging from 4'7 to the tallest being
				just under 6'. Weight wise kitsune are as light and agile as they look.
				Your size is Medium.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed
				is 30 feet. While not carrying anything in your hands you can drop to all
				fours and increase your movement speed to 35 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Kitsune Awareness.</em></strong> You have the
				ability to hear falsehoods for what they are. You know if you hear a
				creature willingly lie. A creature hidden from divination magic reveals
				nothing.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Kitsune Trickery.</em></strong> You can appear
				as a human equivalent of yourself indefinitely using a very simple
				illusion magic, you cannot change alter your illusionary human self.
				A creature looking directly at you can make a Intelligence (Investigation)
				check, to tell that you are not what you appear to be, though they still
				cannot perceive your true form. The DC for this check is equal to
				10 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier. This magic is
				detectable by spells such as detect magic and dispelled in an antimagic
				field or by a successful dispel magic. Your proficiency bonus is considered
				the level of the spell for the sake of dispel magic. If your illusion is
				dispelled you cannot use the effect again until after a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Akihiko, Daiki, Jirou, Kei, Osamu,
				Takeo, Yuudai</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Aya, Chinatsu, Eri, Mana, Ritsuko,
				Sachiko, Tsukiko</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d8">4'5"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d8">75 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="2" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_AWARENESS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_TRICKERY" />
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Kitsune Subrace" supports="Kitsune" optional="false" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Kitsune Awareness" type="Racial Trait" source="dandwiki" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_AWARENESS">
		<description>
			<p>You have the
				ability to hear falsehoods for what they are. You know if you hear a
				creature willingly lie. A creature hidden from divination magic reveals
				nothing.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You know if you hear a creature willingly lie.
				A creature hidden from divination magic reveals nothing.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Kitsune Trickery" type="Racial Trait" source="dandwiki" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_TRICKERY">
		<description>
			<p>You can appear as a human equivalent of yourself indefinitely using a
				very simple illusion magic, you cannot change alter your illusionary
				human self. A creature looking directly at you can make a Intelligence
				(Investigation) check, to tell that you are not what you appear to be,
				though they still cannot perceive your true form. The DC for this check
				is equal to 10 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier. This
				magic is detectable by spells such as detect magic and dispelled in an
				antimagic field or by a successful dispel magic. Your proficiency bonus
				is considered the level of the spell for the sake of dispel magic. If
				your illusion is dispelled you cannot use the effect again until after
				a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can appear as a human equivalent of yourself indefinitely.
				A creature looking directly at you can make a Intelligence (Investigation) check,
				to tell that you are not what you appear to be, though they still cannot
				perceive your true form. (DC = 10 + proficiency bonus + Charisma modifier.)</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Kitsune Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="dandwiki" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_SUBRACE">
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Kitsune Subrace" supports="Kitsune" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Zenko Kitsune" type="Sub Race" source="dandwiki" id="ID_SUB_RACE_ZENKO_KITSUNE">
		<supports>Kitsune</supports>
		<description>
			<p>They are known as celestial kitsune since most are benevolent and kind.
				These kitsune tend to have the lighter fur colors, white, golden brown,
				grey, etc.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Kitsune Divinity.</em></strong>
				You know the produce flame cantrip, with the exception that your flame
				is blue. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the bless spell once per
				long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can also cast the calm emotions
				spell once per long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Second Language.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Celestial.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_DIVINITY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Kitsune Divinity" type="Racial Trait" source="dandwiki" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_DIVINITY">
		<description>You know the produce flame cantrip, with the exception that your flame
		is blue. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the bless spell once per
		long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can also cast the calm emotions
		spell once per long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You know the Produce Flame cantrip, with the exception that your flame is blue.
				Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</description>
			<description level="3">You know the Produce Flame cantrip, with the exception that your flame is blue.
				You can cast Bless 1/Long Rest.
				Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
				<description level="5">You know the Produce Flame cantrip, with the exception that your flame is blue.
					You can cast Bless 1/Long Rest.
					You can cast Calm Emotions 1/Long Rest.
					Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRODUCE_FLAME" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALM_EMOTIONS" level="5"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Second Language Celestial" type="Racial Trait" source="dandwiki" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL">
		<description>
			<p>You can speak, read, and write Celestial.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Language" name="Celestial" id="ID_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL" level="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Yako Kitsune" type="Sub Race" source="dandwiki" id="ID_SUB_RACE_YAKO_KITSUNE">
		<supports>Kitsune</supports>
		<description>
			<p>They are known as trickster kitsune since they are the ones more prone
				to their prankster heritage. These kitsune tend to have the darker fur
				colors, black, reddish brown, dark grey, etc.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Kitsune Arcana.</em></strong>
				You know the produce flame cantrip, with the exception that your flame
				is blue. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast Cause Fear once per long rest.
				When you reach 5th level, you can cast Phantasmal Force once per long rest.
				Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Second Language.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Sylvan.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_ARCANA" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Kitsune Arcana" type="Racial Trait" source="dandwiki" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_KITSUNE_ARCANA">
		<description>You know the produce flame cantrip, with the exception that your flame
		is blue. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the Cause Fear spell once per
		long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can also cast the Phantasmal Force
		spell once per long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.
		</description>
		<sheet>
		<description>You know the Produce Flame cantrip, with the exception that your flame is blue.
			Charisma is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</description>
		<description level="3">You know the Produce Flame cantrip, with the exception that your flame is blue.
			You can cast Cause Fear 1/Long Rest.
			Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
			<description level="5">You know the Produce Flame cantrip, with the exception that your flame is blue.
				You can cast Cause Fear 1/Long Rest.
				You can cast Phantasmal Force 1/Long Rest.
				Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRODUCE_FLAME" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_CAUSE_FEAR" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PHANTASMAL_FORCE" level="5"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Second Language Sylvan" type="Racial Trait" source="dandwiki" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN">
		<description>
			<p>You can speak, read, and write Sylvan.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Language" name="Sylvan" id="ID_LANGUAGE_SYLVAN" level="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- an element that you should grant in a subrace so that you can override stats/infernal legacy -->
	<element name="Kitsune Subrace" type="Grants" source="Internal" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_KITSUNE_SUBRACE" />
</elements>
